A Guide to the Charles Burchard Collection, 1935-1989, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series I: Professional Papers, 1935-1989, n.d.
  Subseries I: Architectural Plans & Drawings, 1940-c.1968, contains drawings, sketches, blueprints, plans, and some photographs and boards relating to professional projects on which Burchard worked. This series primarily represents work done while Burchard was an associate of A. M. Kinney in Ohio, but also includes projects completed later in his career, like his residence in Blacksburg. This subseries is in alphabetical order by project name (for private residences, projects are sorted by last name).
  Subseries J: Certificates, 1938-1960, n.d., includes documentation of architecture and other professional certifications, as well as degrees (BA and MA) and recognitions from Virginia Tech. Items are organized into two sub-groups: architecture-related and degrees & promotions. Within each sub-group, materials are in chronological order.
  - Subseries A: Undergraduate & Graduate Work/Professorship at Harvard, 1935-1953, n.d.
    - MIT: Admission, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Data and Statistics on West Side, New York, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Design of an Entrance to the City of New York, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Issue of Labor, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Problem Analysis Report for Design of an Entrance to the City of New York, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - MIT: Coursework, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Architectural Research, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - MIT: Papers (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - MIT Work: Architecture History (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - MIT Work: Photographs of Architecture Plates (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - MIT Report: Thesis Rough Draft (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - SG Preliminary Report: Building Cost Analysis (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous MIT (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Examination for Architecture License, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Report on Mexico, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Mexico, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Prof. Burchard: Harvard Coursework, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Burchard Notes, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Harvard Coursework Outlines, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lectures: Planning I, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Harvard: Committee for the Reorganization of the Curriculum in Architectural Design, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Lecture: Harvard GSD New First Year Curriculum, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Prof. Burchard: Harvard Coursework, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Exhibition Information: Harvard GSD, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - BAC Lectures, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Black Mountain College Lectures (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - New Hampshire School Reports with Walter Gropius, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Housing Paper, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Prof. Burchard: Harvard Coursework, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Lecture: Light, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Talk: Commonweath Fund Seminar, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Prof. Burchard: Harvard Coursework, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Lecture: Future Design Symposium, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - BAC: New Attitudes & Buildings in Britain, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Modern Architecture: Boston Rotary Club, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Harvard: Work of Students (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 37-40)
    - Miscellaneous: Harvard (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Subseries B: Burchard Trail, Fulbright Fellowship, & Legal-Sized Notes, 1950-1982, n.d. (bulk, 1950-1962)
    - Fulbright, London, Luggage Tags, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Fulbright, London, Travel Documents (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Fulbright, London (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fulbright Trip, London (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - The AA School of Architecture, London (2 folders), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - The Architectural Association School of Architecture, London, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Burchard Trail (5 folders), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
    - Burchard Trail, Articles, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Transcription: Seminar on the Education of Architects, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Charles Burchard Notes (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1st Direction Notes and Elaborations (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Infants School (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Readings Frampton (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Subseries C: A. M. Kinney Firm: Architectural Projects, 1960-1979, n.d.
    - Aiken Senior High School, Ohio, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Aiken High School Technical Drawings, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Amanda Junior High School, Middletown, Ohio (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Brodie Complex, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - CB Photography: Mabley & Carew Building, Fountain Square, Ohio, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Chemistry Building, University of Cincinnati, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Christ Episcopal Church, Blacksburg, Va (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Design Manual for Parish House, Cincinnati, Ohio (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Du Page Memorial Hospital (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Evangelical Luthern Church of the Cross (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Hilltop School (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Madeira Schools (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Mandlestamm Residence: Depostion, Blacksburg, Va, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Methodist Home for the Aged (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Miles Laboratories, New Haven, CT, 1960-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - A.M. Kinney, Municple Pool & Bathohouse, St. Bernard, Ohio (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - North College Hill Elementary School (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - North Fairmount Junior High School (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Perspective Drawings, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Post Office, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - St. Paul Community Methodist Church (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - St. Paul Community Methodist Church (Ohio) (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - A.M. Kinney, Thomson Cadillac (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - A.M. Kinney: Tom's River (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Trinity Episcopal Church (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - University Master Plan (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Washington Park Elementary School (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Washington Park Elementary School, Photographs and Drawings (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - A.M. Kinney, Westley Child Care Center (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Unnamed Projects
      - Books: Schools (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Building Dedications (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Church, Technical Drawings (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous: Models (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Miscellaneous & Unidentified Churches (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Miscellaneous & Unidentified Project Photographs and Drawings (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Miscellaneous & Unidentified: Project Technical Plans (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Miscellaneous & Unidentified School Photographs and Drawings (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Presentation Boards and Technical Drawings from A. M. Kinney projects (Box 25, Box 26, Box 27)
  - Subseries D: A. M. Kinney Firm: Office Documents and Memos, 1954-1964, n.d.
    - General Reference, 1954-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Articles of Partnership, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - A.M. Kinney: Interoffice Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - A.M Kinney: Project Books (28) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Analysis of Failed Columns (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Sales (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous Professional, 1936-1961, n.d.
    - Reinhard & Hofmeister Architects, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Military Service Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fairchild Aircraft Division: Duramold, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Faircrafts: Duramold Article, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Duramold: Burlington Laboratories Dura-Repair, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fairchild: Solar Radiation Studies, 1943-1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fairchild: Photographs, Tennis Courts, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fairchild: Tennis Courts, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tennis Court & House Design for Sherman Fairchild, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fairchild Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - American Society of Planners and Architects, 1942-1948 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Letters of Recommendation, 1946-1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Burchard-Lyman Architects, Ledgers, 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Theatre Design for Sherman Fairchild, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Almy, Bigelow, & Washburn, Salem, Ma (1/2), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Almy, Bigelow, & Washburn, Salem, Ma (2/2), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mansur, Hyannis, Ma, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Jaworski House, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Carrol F Jacobs House, Nahant, Ma, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Benedict & Lawrence Houses with Perkins, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Comittee on Intergration of Design & Construction, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Design Construction Intergration, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Agoos House, East Andover, NH, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Burchard-Lyman Architects, Ledgers, 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Dimond House, Cambridge, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Hill Residence, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Agoos Residence, Chesnut Hill, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Agoos Residence, East Andover, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Southwest Research Institute, School Building Research Report, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Charles Burchard Portfolio, c.1960 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Preliminary Study for the University of Cincinnati (2 folders), 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 31-32)
    - Campus Plans for the University of Illinios, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Charles Burchard, Portfolio (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Burchard-Lyman House: Interior Photograph (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Design Awards (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - House by the Sea Sketches (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous Technical Drawings (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Ohio School Economy Studies (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Organic Elementary School Planning & Design (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Photographs: Schools (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Schools: General (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Sketches & Diagrams (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Warm Hearth, Inc, Blacksburg, Va (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Subseries F: Papers & Talks, 1940-1984, n.d.
    - Sub-subseries 1: By Date
      - Art and Design Education, 1940-1950 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Talks and Writings of Others, 1947-1989 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Talks and Lectures (3 folders), 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 40-42)
      - Presentations, 1952-1984 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Architecture and Environment, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Paper on Lateral Forces, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Architecture "Frills", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - The Architect and the Business Community, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Professionals in Society Conference, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Architecture: An Environment Art, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Architecture: An Art Which Society Produces, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Writings on University Curriculum, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - The Education of an Architect, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - The University Environmental Department, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Home Economics Association Convention: Who Is Responsible for Urban Envirnoment, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Architecture Environment Design, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - AIA Meeting: Growth and Change, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - UVa Conference Talk: The Care and Feeding of Architects, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Study of the Profession of Landscape Architecture, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - AIA Journal: Dialouge and Discovery, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Art and Design Education, 1970-1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Toward an Urban and rural Dev. Policy for Va, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Ding and Echols: Education for Environmental Systems Design, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Ferrari: Language Teaching- A New Approach that is Geared to Our Times, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - The Shifting Scale of Housing Design and Technology, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Black Mountain Interview with Mary Harris, 1971-1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Profession of Landscape Architecture, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Poulton: Centenial Publication- History of the College of Architecture, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Burchard: The Next Horizon, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Arizonia State University: Architecture- Evolution of an Acedemic Purpose, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Burchard for AIA: Education for Architecture and Environmental Design, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - The Role of Technology for Housing the Poor, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Burchard: Urbanization of a Planet, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - A Vessel of Promise, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Honors Colloquium, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Buckminster Fuller, 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Lecture Notes, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Chicago Seminar on the Education of Architect, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Simutis: Computing in Architecture Education: A Statement of Direction, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Sub-subseries 2: By Title (Undated)
      - Abstracts of Published Work and Originals (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Architecture: the Historic Present (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - The Critical Curve: 1840-1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Education: A Shift in Focus (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - The Human Habitat (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - The Human Habit: Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - The Human Habitat: Rough Drafts (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Human Settlements (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 36-37)
      - Human Settlements: Articles (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Megolopolis Talk Notes (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - On the Direction of Design Education (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Student Papers (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Talks and Writings (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 44, Box 7, Folder 1-2)
      - Misc. Lecture Notes (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Misc. Writings (8 folders) (Box 7, Folder 6-13)
  - Subseries G: Articles and Newspaper Clippings
    - Articles about Burchard (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 14-17)
  - Subseries H: Professional Memberships & Organizations, 1959-1989
    - Sub-subseries 1: Alpha Rho Chi (APX)
      - APX: Buckminster Fuller Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - APX: Constitution and By-Laws, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - The Archi, Magazine of APX, 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Alpha Rho Chi: Professional Development Program, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Alpha Rho Chi: Convention, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - APX Magazine: The New Horizon, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - APX Convention: Burchard & I.M. Pei Photos, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - APX Financial Statements, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Alpha Rho Chi: National Convention, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - APX Expenses (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Alpha Rho Chi: Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Sub-subseries 2: American Institute of Architects (AIA)
      - AIA Publications & Documents, 1950-1963 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - AIA Education Research Project, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - 71st AIA Annual Convention, New York, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - AIA: Princeton Report Analysis, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - AIA: Journal Diagrams, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - AIA: Journal, 1969-1978 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - VA AIA: Awards Discussion, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - AIA: Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Documents on AIA Award Nominations (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 25-29)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture (ACSA)
      - ACSA: Talks, 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - ACSA: Journal of Architectural Education, 1959-1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - ACSA: Articles, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - ACSA: VA. Consortium for Curriculum Implementation, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - ACSA: Reorganization, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - ACSA: Proposals, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - ACSA: Performance Specifications for Environmental Design Professonials of the Future, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - ACSA: Federal Council Research Survey, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - ACSA: Environmental Design Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - ACSA: Environmental Desgin Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - ACSA: Environmental Design Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - ACSA: Environmental Design Conference, NSF Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - ACSA: AIA, Research Committee, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - ACSA: Study, Arch. Education Committee (2 folders), 1974 (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
      - ACSA: JAE Endowment, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - ACSA Charlston Notes on Frampton, Ventom, and Herdeg, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - ACSA: News, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - ACSA/AIA: Award for Excellence in Architectual Education, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - ACSA/AIA: Award for Excellence in Architecural Education, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - ACSA: Symposium, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - ACSA: Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Design Art Corporation, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - NSID, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - IAWA (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Subseries I: Architectural Plans & Drawings, 1940-c.1968
    - Agoo, Mr. and Mrs. H. M., Weekend House (East Andover, NH)
      - 5 board with elevations and plans (Folder 1)
      - 10 sheets of plans, site plans, and elevations, 1949-1950 (Folder 3)
    - Aiken Senior High School (Cincinnati, OH), plans (A. M. Kinney project) (Folder 4)
    - Apartment proposal, 5 photocopies of sketches (Folder 3)
    - Andrews, Allen, House (Arlington, VA)
      - 3 photocopies of plans and elevations, 1950 (Folder 2)
      - Plot plans, foundation plans and masonry details, elevations, sections, details, 1950-1951 (Folder 6)
    - Burchard House (Blacksburg, VA)
      - Site plan, elevations, plans (Folder 7)
      - Plans (upper floor, main floor, lower level, foundation), interior set of drawings, elevations, details, 1968 (Folder 6)
      - Plans and drawings (Box 31)
    - City Center charcoal/color drawing (Folder 1)
    - City Hall project
      - 7 photocopies of elevations and plans, 1940 (Folder 2)
    - Department store (Cincinnati, OH), board with color photograph, 1961 (Folder 1)
    - Drawing of an unknown school building (Folder 1)
    - Elementary School Building (Madeira, OH), plans (A. M. Kinney project) (Folder 5)
    - Feasibility Study: A Center for Science and Industry at the Cincinnati Union Terminal (A. M. Kinney project), drawings (Folder 4)
    - Hale House (Marblehead, MA), plans, elevations, site plan, 1953 (Folder 6)
    - Harvard GSD (Graduate School Design?), set of plans, elevations, and sections, 1939 (Folder 6)
    - "Housing Apartment Arrangement for a 100 Acre Land Unit"
      - 3 photocopies of plans and elevations, c.1940s (Folder 2)
      - Boards (Folder 4)
    - Jacobs, Mrs. Carroll F., Residence (Nahant, MA)
      - 4 boards with floor plans; 1 floor plan, 1947 (Folder 3)
      - Plans, elevations, sections, site and key plans, details, perspective sketches, 1947-1948 (Folder 6)
    - Medical Practice (Norwich, CT), plans, c.1950 (Box 32)
    - Miles Research Laboratory, plans (A. M Kinney project) (Box 32)
    - No. 120 Broadway (Norwich, CT), preliminaries, 1952 (Folder 6)
    - Planning: A Study in Cambridge, Mass, 17 sheets of maps, c.1946 (Folder 3)
    - Reading Shopping Center, 4 photocopies of plans and elevations (Folder 2)
    - Science Complex-Engineering Complex, University of Cincinnati, plans (A. M. Kinney project), plans, 1965 (Folder 4)
    - Settlement House design, 2 sheets (Folder 3)
    - "Shore House," 4 photocopies of plans and elevations, 1941 (Folder 2)
    - Smallwood House (Raleigh, NC), preliminary blueprint (Box 31)
    - Tomkins House, electrical plans and details, 1946 (Folder 4)
    - The Towers (Cincinnati, OH), plans (A. M. Kinney project) (Folder 4)
    - Train Station (New York City), drawing/charcoal (Box 33)
    - Underground Bus Terminal and Parking Facility (Cincinnati, OH), Presentation brochure (A. M. Kinney project) (Folder 4)
    - Unidentified office building, site plan (Folder 7)
    - Unknown project, handdrawn perspectives in pencil (Folder 6)
    - Unidentified residence, 3 pencil sketches, 7 drawings and plans (Folder 2)
    - Unidentified school room, 2 drawings (Folder 3)
    - Unidentified southern elevation and 3 detail sketches (Folder 7)
    - Unidentified suburban shopping center
      - Charcoal site plan, elevations and plans (Folder 4)
      - Boards (Box 4)
    - U. S. Junior Chamber of Commerce building (Washington, DC), 8 sheets of plans and views (Folder 3)
  - Subseries J: Certificates, 1938-1981
    - Architecture Related
      - The American Institute of Architects, 1971 (Folder 8)
      - The Architect's Oath (Folder 7)
      - Certificate, County Clerk's Office, County of New York registration, 1940 (Folder 7)
      - Commonwealth of Massachusetts Board of Registration of Architects certification, 1941 (Folder 7)
      - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania certification, 1955 (Folder 7)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia, Advisory Research Committee on Plans and Specifications for School Buildings, 1968 (Folder 8)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia certification, 1964 (Folder 7)
      - National Council of Architecture Registration Boards certification and letter, 1954 (Folder 7)
      - North Carolina Board of Architecture Certification (Folder 7)
      - The School Executive 1955 Competition for Better School Design Honorable Mention Citation. presented to A. M. Kinney Associates, Charles Burchard, Architect for design of North College Hill Elementary School, April 1956 (Folder 7)
      - South Dakota State Board of Engineering & Architectural Examiners certification, 1959 (Folder 7)
      - State Board of Iowa Board of Architectural Examiners certification (Folder 7)
      - State of Connecticut certification, 1958 (Folder 7)
      - State of Indiana certification, 1958 (Folder 7)
      - State of Kentucky certification, 1959 (Folder 7)
      - State of Michigan Board of Registration for Architects, Professional Engineers, and Land Surveyors certification, 1958 (Folder 7)
      - State of New Jersey certification, 1960 (Folder 7)
      - State of Ohio certification, 1955 (Folder 7)
      - University of the State of New York Education Department Architecture certification, 1940 (Folder 7)
      - Virginia Foundation for Architectural Education, Certification of Appreciation, 1981 (Folder 8)
    - Degrees & Promotions
      - MIT degree, Bachelor in Architecture, 1938 (Folder 7)
      - Harvard University degree, Master of Architecture, 1948 (Folder 7)
      - Virginia Tech, Board of Visitors, Promotion to University Professor (3 copies), 1972 (Folder 8)
- Series II: College of Architecture, Program & Curriculum, 1959-1987, n.d.
  Series II: College of Architecture, Program & Curriculum, 1959-1987, n.d., consists of five subseries. Subseries A: Proposals & Studies, 1961-1980, includes proposals for majors, courses, and departments added to the College of Architecture during Burchard's tenure, as well as materials relating to a new building request in the early 1960s. This subseries is in chronological order.
  Subseries B: VPI College of Architecture Self Studies & NAAB Accreditation Materials, 1959-1980, consists of materials collected for and using in the course of college self-studies, for long-range college planning, and for accreditation by the National Architectural Accrediting Board. This subseries is in chronological order. This subseries is in chronological order.